埃迪:感谢你,我的好人.
Ed: And my thanks to you my good man.
出租车司机:三十四块.
Taxi Driver: That's thirty four even.
埃迪:我就回来.
Ed: I'll be right back.
出租车司机:嘿,如果我知道我需要等,
Taxi Driver: Hey, if I knew I was going to have to wait,
我应该关计价器了.
I wouldn't have turned off the meter.
埃迪:我知道.(在想)哦,上帝给我力量.(大声的)行了,
Ed: I know.(In his head) Oh god give me strength.(Aloud) Alright,
说出来,恩,小东西.
spread em clown!
本:说什么?外公,埃迪!
Ben: Spread what?Grandpa Ed!
埃迪:哈哈,本.
Ed: Ha ha Bennie.
听着;你高兴见到我吗?
Listen, are you happy to see me?
本:当然,外公.
Ben: Sure grandpa.
埃迪:见到我你激动吗?
Ed: Are you thrilled to see me?
本:你说对了,外公.
Ben: You bet grandpa.
埃迪:能借我34块吗?
Ed: Got thirty four bucks I can borrow?
本:你是谁呀?
Ben: Who are you?
埃迪:别慌!你父母在哪里?
Ed: Keep your pants on!Where are your folks?
本:睡觉呢.
Ben: In bed.
埃迪:不错,不错,不错.如果这不是美丽的图画.杰森.哦,杰森.
Ed: Well, well, well.If this isn't a pretty picture.Jaaason.Oh Jason.
杰森:哦,小甜心.
Jason: Oh sweetheart.
埃迪:不,杰森!起来!
Ed: No Jason!Get up!
杰森:不,迈克,机关枪.哦!啊,埃迪,你在我的卧室里干什么?
Jason: No Mike, the machine gun.No.Ah Ed, what are you doing in my bedroom?
埃迪:一个更重要的问题是,你跟我女儿在干嘛?
Ed: A more important question might be what are you doing with my daughter?
杰森:我们结婚了.
Jason: We are married.
埃迪:哦,你认为这样就行了.亲亲你爸爸怎么样?
Ed: Oh, you think that makes it ok.How about a little kiss for your dad.
杰森:啊,啊,别,别,别!
Jason: Ah, ah, please, pelease, pelease!
埃迪:他是不是经常在早上脾气暴躁?
Ed: Is he always this grumpy in the morning?
麦琪:我希望爸爸告诉我他要来.我今天没时间和他谈.
Maggie: I wish my dad told me he was coming.
我今天没有时间呼吸.我告诉你,
I don't have time to talk to him today.I don't have time to breath today.
他肯定有什么事情.
I tell you, that he is up to something.
要不然怎么他会跑了两百里路过来,却没有和我妈妈一起.
Why else would he travel two hundred miles without bringing my mum.
杰森:嗨,麦琪,我们谈论的是你妈妈.
Jason: Hey Maggie, this is your mother we are talking about.
麦琪:杰森,我妈妈不会让我爸爸不安的.
Maggie: Jason, my mum does not get on my dad's nerves.
爸爸几年前就不听她的话了.
He stopped listening to her years ago.
杰森:那么你认为她来干什么呢?
Jason: Well what do you think he's up to then?
麦琪:哦,
Maggie: Oh I don't know,
我不知道,我总觉得这次我会结束感到内疚,
but somehow I know I am going to end up feeling guilty and then I'm going
然后把气撒在你头上.
to take it out on you.
杰森:我今晚会工作的很晚.
Jason: I'll be working late tonight.
埃迪:哦,没人做出像你做的果酱烤薄饼.
Ed: Oh, nobody makes blueberry pancakes like you do Margaret.
麦琪:哦,这些不是果酱烤薄饼.
Maggie: oh those aren't blueberry pancakes.
埃迪:哦.
Ed: Oh.
杰森:哦,很好.
Jason: Oh, that was good.Very funny Ed.
非常有趣,埃迪.小孩子们的好榜样.
And such a good example for the little one.
迈克:嗨,各位.什么这么有趣?
Mike: Hey every body.What's so funny?
埃迪:迈克!
Ed: Mikey!
迈克:嗨,外公,埃迪.
Mike: Hey Grandpa Ed!
埃迪:名演员好吗?
Ed: How's the famous actor.
迈克:好.
Mike: Good.
埃迪:你和米歇尔 皮弗尔演过爱情戏吗?
Ed: Have you done any love scenes with that Michelle Piefer yet?
杰森:他名字是菲佛,米歇尔 菲佛.
Jason: Her name is Pfeiffer, Michelle Pfeiffer.
迈克:为什么没人告诉我外公过来?
Mike: Why did nobody tell me that grandpa was coming over?
麦琪:我们没人知道.
Maggie: None of us knew.
埃迪:啊,真荒谬.
Ed: Ah, that's ridiculous.I phones yesterday.
我昨天打过电话.我不会不打电话就过来.
I wouldn't barge on in without called.
杰森:行了,埃迪.你通常过来不打电话的.
Jason: Come on Ed.You always barge on in without calling.
埃迪:我事实上打了电话.我给本留了口信,就像我通常那样做的.
Ed: The hell I do.I left a message with Bennie, just like I always do.
麦琪:通常那样做!
Maggie: Always do!
埃迪:是呀.
Ed: Yeah.
杰森:那么这些年来,你从来没有擅自过来?
Jason: So all these years you haven't been barging in?
埃迪:我应该说没有.
Ed: I should say not.
本:我没有告诉你们吗?
Ben: Didn't I tell you guys?
杰森和麦琪:没有.
Jason and Maggie: No.
开萝尔:好极了.而且毕竟我们已经给你带愚蠢的口信.
Carol: Great.And after all those stupid messages we've taken for you.
那么,你还有什么忘记告诉我们了?
So, what else have you forgotten to tell us?
本:恩,迈克,朱莉打电话过来.她说婚礼取消了.
Ben: Um, Mike, Julie called.She said the wedding's off.
麦琪:爸爸,你还没回答我的问题呢.你为什么来这?
Maggie: Dad, you still haven't answered my question.Why are you here?
埃迪:没有那么多原因.只是突然想来看看.
Ed: No reason.Just a spur of the moment visit.
我想也许我们可以整天的坐着,说说话.
I thought maybe we could sit around all day and talk.
你们知道,闲谈和看看墙上贴了什么.
You know, chew the fat and see what sticks to the wall.
麦琪:难怪妈妈呆在家里.
Maggie: No wonder mum stayed at home.
埃迪:我们先干什么?
Ed: What can we do first?
麦琪:对不起,爸爸,但是你恰巧挑了个非常坏的日子.
Maggie: I'm sorry dad, but you just picked a very bad day.
埃迪:那么我认为也许我们能出去吃麦芽糖,啊?
Ed: Well I thought maybe we could all go out for malts, hu?
麦琪:哦,爸爸.
Maggie: Oh dad, I've got this PTA thing and these two articles that are
我有家庭教师协会的事情,还有下周五截止的两篇文章,而我还没有开始写.
due next Friday and I haven't even started them yet.
埃迪:那么你还是对"跳房子"游戏很疯狂.
Ed: Say are you still crazy about hopscotch.
麦琪:爸爸,爸爸,我不行.你在听吗?我真不行.
Maggie: Dad, dad, I can't.Are you listening?I really can't.
埃迪:好吧.你走吧.
Ed: Alright.Go on.Don't trouble yourself over me.Go on about your business.
别让我麻烦你了.
Forget that I am here.Forget that I flew two hundred miles.
快干你的事吧.忘了我在这里.
Forget that I took a cab.
忘了我飞了两百公里.
Forget that I brought you into this world;
忘了我搭计程车.忘了我把你带到这个世上;抚养你十八个痛苦的年头.
put a roof over your head for eighteen miserable years.
克莉丝:你还忘了那部分,她那次胫骨骨折,
Chrissy: You left out the part about carrying her six miles to the hospital
背着她走了六里路到医院.
when she fractured he tibia.
埃迪:正确.在暴风雪天.
Ed: Right.In the snowstorm.
克莉丝:三英尺厚.
Chrissy: With the three foot drifts.
埃迪:没穿鞋.
Ed: Without any shoes on.
麦琪:谢谢你,克莉丝.
Maggie: Thank you Chrissy.
克莉丝:有一群狼在追你.
Chrissy: With a wild pack of wolves chasing you.
埃迪:幼儿园,哈?
Ed: Playschool hu?
麦琪:啊哈.
Maggie: Ah hu.
埃迪:我猜想让一个陌生人带孩子,
Ed: I guess having your kids raised by strangers beats having them raised
要比她的亲生母亲带强.
by their own flesh and blood mothers, hu?
麦琪:爸爸!没关系.
Maggie: Daddy!Never mind.
埃迪:那老师看上去对我来说太年轻.
Ed: That teacher there looked mighty young to me.
他们能找你这年纪的老师吗?
Could they find somebody your age?
麦琪:谢谢,爸爸.爸爸,听着,
Maggie: Thanks dad.Dad look, I'm sorry this day is going to be so hectic;
我很抱歉,我今天太忙了;我得去……爸爸!爸爸,车在这里.
I just got to...Dad!Dad, the car's over here.
埃迪:过来坐,麦琪 凯瑟林,享受充实的一天.
Ed: Come sit down Margaret Catherine and enjoy this crummy day.
麦琪:爸爸,我得去银行,
Maggie: Dad, I've got to get to the bank and I have this PTA thing and
得去家庭教师协会,我还得开始写这些文章.
I still have those articles to start.
埃迪:你看见那里头发浓密的英俊的年轻人了吗?
Ed: You see that handsome young man over there with the bushy hair?
麦琪:爸爸,你在听吗?
Maggie: Dad, are you listening?
埃迪:推女儿荡秋千的人.
Ed: The one pushing his daughter on the swing.
麦琪:爸爸,我最好放弃.
Maggie: Dad, I might as well give up.
埃迪:是.现在说,他让你想起什么人?
Ed: Yep.Now say, does he remind you of anyone?
麦琪:没有.
Maggie: No.
埃迪:你非常关心的人.
Ed: Someone you car about very much.
麦琪:不是.
Maggie: No.
埃迪:和你非常亲近的人.
Ed: Someone you are very close to.
埃迪:不是.
Maggie: No.
埃迪:和你非常靠近的人,现在.
Ed: Someone you are very close to right now.
麦琪:爸爸,我没时间猜谜.
Maggie: Daddy, I do not have time for a guessing game.
埃迪:那么我给你一点提示.他和我一模一样,
Ed: Well then let me give you a hint.
当你那么大的时候.
He is the spitting image of me when you were that age.
麦琪:爸爸,你从来没有浓密的头发.你就没有头发.
Maggie: Daddy, you never had bushy hair.You never had hair.
埃迪:见鬼,麦琪.我们在这就不能享有温柔的时刻吗?
Ed: Damn it Maggie.Can't we have one stinking tender moment here?
麦琪:好的.你有头发.
Maggie: Ok.You had hair.
埃迪:我不是说头发;我说的是红色秋千,
Ed: I'm not talking about the hair;
我曾经在后院推你玩的.
I'm talking about the big red swing I used to push you on in the backyard.
记得吗?
Remember?
麦琪:爸爸,我们后院从来没有红色秋千.
Maggie: Daddy, we never had a red swing in the backyard.
埃迪:好了,是在公园里的大秋千,那里流氓曾经拿刀打架.
Ed: Ok, it was a crummy swing in the park, where all the gangs used
to hold their knife fights
麦琪:那么你为什么之前不说?
Maggie: Well then why didn't you say so?
埃迪:这是回忆.我想使它更美妙.
Ed: It was a memory.I was trying to make it nicer.
麦琪:爸爸,出什么事了?
Maggie: Daddy, is something wrong?
埃迪:我们本来应该这会深陷于怀旧.
Ed: Well we were supposed to be knee deep in nostalgia at this point.
我怎么知道你会这么无礼?
How was I to know that you were going to be so rude?
麦琪:我无礼? 爸爸,谁走进别人的卧室,而她正和她丈夫躺在一起.
Maggie: I'm being rude!Dad, who is the one who walked into the others bedroom
when she was lying with her husband
埃迪:钓鱼.
Ed: Fishing.
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
埃迪:钓鱼能对你前额的皱纹有奇效.
Ed: Fishing would do wonders for those creases in your forehead.
麦琪:我前额没有皱纹.我是说,
Maggie: I do not have creases in my forehead.
也许有一两条细纹,
I mean, maybe a fine line or two, but definitely not ...forget it.
但绝对不是……算了.钓鱼怎么样?
What about fishing?
埃迪:好呀,你对我叫,当我刚要请你去钓鱼.
Ed: Fine, shout at me when I have just invited you to go on a
fishing trip
麦琪:爸爸,你没邀请我钓鱼.
Maggie: Dad, you didn't invite me to go on a fishing trip.
埃迪:我当然邀请了.
Ed: Of course I did.
为什么我提起那次钓鱼,那年你才六岁?
Why else would I bring up that fishing trip we took when you were six
还把我的所有的鱼倒进河里.
years old?And drowned all my night crawlers.
麦琪:爸爸,你没提这事.
Maggie: Daddy, you did not bring it up.
埃迪:麦琪,刚才你确实没有听我说话?
Ed: Maggie, just when exactly did you stop listening to me?
麦琪:爸爸,你没有提这事.
Maggie: Daddy, you did not bring it up.
埃迪:瞧,
Ed: See, you've got me so confused.
你把我都弄糊涂了.和你说话比和你妈更糟.
Talking to you is worse than talking to your mother.
我不知道我怎么样容忍你们中任一个的.
I don't know hwy I put up with either one of you.
麦琪:如果我们中有一个刚才蛮不讲理的话,是你.
Maggie: If either one of us is not making sense around here right now,
现在你来这里,你希望我们放下一切事情,
it's you.Now you come here,
放开红地毯.
you expect us to drop everything and roll out the red carpet.
你在这个世界上没有工作.你是退休的人.
You don't have a care ion the world.You're retired.
埃迪:我要死了!
Ed: I'm dying!
麦琪:干什么去?
Maggie: To do what?
埃迪:不,我飞了两百里路就是想告诉你.我要死了.
Ed: No, that's what I flew two hundred miles to tell you.I'm dying.
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
埃迪:还是忘了它吧.你忙.
Ed: Just forget about it.You're busy.
杰森:请接赖莉医生.西维尔打的长途.
Jason: Doctor Riley please.Doctor Seaver calling long distance.Yes thank you.
好,谢谢你.我等一下.
I'll hold.
开萝尔:克莉丝,轻打你的皇后.
Carol: Chrissy, tap your queen.
埃迪:感觉良好.感觉就绪.仍在舞蹈.
Ed: Feeling good.Feeling ready.Still dancing.
麦琪:看着他.他完全忘记了他给我带来的烦恼.
Maggie: Look at him.He is totally oblivious to the worry he has caused me.
杰森:是呀,赖莉医生.我是杰森 西维尔.我是埃迪的女婿,我们有点担心他.啊哈.
Jason: Yeah, doctor Riley.I'm Jason Seaver, I'm Ed Malone's son in law and we
are a little concerned about him.Uh hu
麦琪:我明白了.我明白了.
Maggie: I got it.I got it.That is not a doctor.
那不是医生.
That number he gave us is just one of dad's Crony's and this is just one
他给我们的电话号码是爸爸的老朋友的,这只是一个大的恶作剧.
big practical joke.
麦琪:哈啊.非常有趣,笑到你这个家伙清醒过来.
Maggie: Ha ha.Very funny, laugh till you sober up you bum.
杰森:请,别,请继续.
Jason: Please, no, please go on.
麦琪:为什么他那样做?
Maggie: Why would he do that?
杰森:全血检查.
Jason: A full blood panel.
麦琪:而且为什么妈妈不和他来?
Maggie: And why isn't mum with him?
杰森:心肌炎.
Jason: Cardiomeopathy.
麦琪:他为什么坐飞机和出租车?他比杰森廉价.
Maggie: Why would he take a plane and a cab?He's cheaper than Jason.
杰森:不,谢谢你对我们这么坦白.再见.亲爱的,恩……
Jason: No, thank you for being so candid with us.Bye.Honey um...
麦琪:他要死了.
Maggie: He's dying?
杰森:我想我在这可以说些什么.
Jason: I wish I could say something here.
麦琪:哦,不.不,一定是哪弄错了.
Maggie: Oh no.no, there must be some mistake.He looks so healthy.
他看起来那么健康.我们需要得到复诊结果.我们只是……
We just need to get a second opinion.We just...
杰森:赖莉医生有复诊结果.
Jason: Doctor Riley was the second opinion.
麦琪:他是?
Maggie: He was?
杰森:是的,瞧,心肌炎是一种病毒感染.
Jason: Yes, see cardiomeopathy is a viral infection.
它影响心肌的功能,起先是轻微绞痛.然后就恶化……
It affects the heart muscles and at
first it is a mild angina.Then it develops into degeneration
麦琪:我将失去我的父亲.
Maggie: I'll lose my daddy.
杰森:对不起,亲爱的,我听医生说……
Jason: Sorry honey, I heard the doctor talk...
麦琪:哦,杰森,我不知道做什么.
Maggie: Oh Jason I don't know what to do.
杰森:好了,亲爱的,你认为他需要什么呢?
Jason: Well honey, what do you think he wants?
麦琪:你什么意思?
Maggie: What do you mean?
杰森:他远道赶来.他过来把这个事情告诉你之外,
Jason: Well he's come all this way.
还有其他事情,亲爱的.
It's for more than just to break the news to you honey.
他在考虑什么事情.你认为那是什么事情?
There's something on his mind.What do you think it is?
麦琪:你知道什么?我真的对我爸爸了解不足以去猜.
Maggie: You know what?I don't really know my father well enough to guess.
埃迪:三次中我赢了两次.我猜你确实从你繁忙的计划安排中为我抽出了些时间,
Ed: I won two out of three.
啊?
Well I guess you did find time in your busy schedule for me, hu?
麦琪:爸爸,对不起.
Maggie: Daddy, I'm sorry.
埃迪:那么,那就是我养大一个女权主义者所得到的.
Ed: Well, that's what I get for raising a woman's libber.
麦琪:爸爸.我不想去散步.
Maggie: Dad.I don't want to go for a walk.
埃迪:晚上真冷.
Ed: It's a cold night.
麦琪:哦,爸爸.哦,爸爸.
Maggie: Oh dad, oh dad.
埃迪:嗨,嗨,嗨.我不需要眼泪.好吗.
Ed: Hey, hey hey.I don't need any tears.Ok.
麦琪:我能为你做什么,爸爸?
Maggie: What can I do for you dad?
埃迪:为我做?
Ed: Do for me!
麦琪:无论你需要什么,你都会得到.
Maggie: Whatever you want you got it.
埃迪:亲爱的,我,哦,啊,那个遗嘱和其他一些重要证件,你得知道它们在走廊壁橱的那个大鞋箱里,就在我的钓具后面.
Ed: Honey, I'm...Oh, uh, that the will and other important papers, you got to know they are in that big shoe box in the hall closet right behind my fishing tackle.
麦琪:啊哈.
Maggie: Uh hu.
埃迪:还有,啊,
Ed: And uh, I've made the funeral arrangements with Flaherty and Son mortuary.
我已经和弗拉提和他儿子的殡仪馆安排好了葬事.到时候一定要找老弗拉提,因为小弗拉提是个白痴.
Be sure to ask for Flaherty senior, because Flaherty Junior is an idiot.
麦琪:爸爸,我们真的必须现在处理所有这些事情吗?
Maggie: Daddy, do we really have to deal with all this now?
埃迪:这很重要.
Ed: This is important.It's about my police death benefits.
关于我警察的死亡抚恤金.
I've asked for monthly payments,
我已经要求月付,可别让那个管办公室的女人告诉你任何不同方面.
and don't let the woman who runs the office tell you any different.
她是个满脸疣的的红发女人.
She's the big read head with all the warts.
麦琪:爸爸,
Maggie: Daddy, did you really come all this way to tell me about a red
你真的远道而来就是为了告诉我一个满脸疣的的红发女人 ?
headed woman with warts?
埃迪:听着,如果你觉得太多不能处理,
Ed: Listen, if this is going to be too much for you to handle,
我可以自己来处理这些事情,从我死后.
I can take care of the whole thing myself, from beyond the grave.
麦琪:爸爸,我不是说……妈妈对这事怎么看?
Maggie: Daddy, I didn't mean....How's mum taking this?
埃迪:哦,他很好.
Ed: Oh she's fine.
麦琪:她怎么对你好……
Maggie: How could she be fine with you...
埃迪:哦,那个遗嘱.
Ed: Oh, the will.What was it about the will?
这关于遗嘱有什么事情?替我制作遗嘱的律师不干了.
The attorney that made out the will doesn't practice anymore.
他去写星期六夜生活.但是他的搭档还在.
He's writing for Saturday night live.Burt his partner is still there.
那家伙根本没趣.现在我猜那就是了.
But he aint funny at all.Now I guess that's it.
麦琪:这就是你到这要告诉我的?一钱不值!
Maggie: That is what you came here to tell me?One napkins worth!
埃迪:亲爱的,我是……有件关于我的事,你并不了解,麦琪.这是一个绝对秘密.这些年,我就一直藏在心理.甚至从你出生的那天开始.
Ed: Honey, I'm s...There is something that you don't know about me Margaret Catherine.It's a deep dark secret.I've kept it way down deep inside of me all these many years.Ever since the day of your birth.
麦琪:什么,爸爸?
Maggie: What daddy?
埃迪:那晚我们在凯尔塞酒吧,我们接到电话说出生很顺利,而且你妈妈还清醒,还有你很好……那晚在那我对自己发了誓,无论什么时候,我要永远不让你知道,我,我,那,我……
Ed: that night at Kelsey's bar when we got the phone call to say that all this birthing business was fine and that your mother was conscious and that you were fine...I made an oath to myself, right there and then, that I would never let you know, I, well I....
麦琪:要个儿子.
Maggie: Wanted a son.
埃迪:你知道?
Ed: You know?
麦琪:直到我十多岁,你总抽雪茄,
Maggie: Until I was in my teens you used to smoke those cigars with "It's
环上面有"这是一个男孩".
a boy" on the rings.
埃迪:雪茄挺不错.我舍不得扔掉它们.
Ed: They were good cigars.I could just throw them away.
麦琪:你把我的第一个洋娃娃烧掉了.
Maggie: You set my first doll on fire.
埃迪:嗨,那是一次意外事故,
Ed: Hey well that was an accident.
烦人的凯茜不该把洋娃娃的嘴放到我的电焊枪那.
Chatty Cathy should have kept her mouth closed around my welding equipment.
麦琪:你要我试训男孩棒球队.
Maggie: You had me try out for little league.
埃迪:但是只要你打个好球,我就允许你化妆.
Ed: But then I always let you wear make up when you got an extra base.
麦琪:你把我培养成运动员.
Maggie: You bought me a jock.
埃迪:我不想让你觉得和其他男孩有任何不同.
Ed: I didn't want you to feel any different from the other guys.
麦琪:哦,爸爸,
Maggie: Oh daddy, this isn't exactly news to me.
这对我来说不是新闻.难道这就是你来这要告诉我的?
Is this really what you came here to tell me?
埃迪:好吧,拒绝一个快死的人最后道歉.
Ed: Fine, deny a dying man his final apology.
麦琪:爸爸,我一直知道你想要个儿子,
Maggie: Daddy, I always knew you wanted a son,
但是我也知道你爱我.多的可能让你吃惊.
but I also knew that you loved me.So much that it probably surprised you.
埃迪:哦,是这样.
Ed: Oh that it did.
麦琪:你看见你哭了,在我婚礼上.
Maggie: I saw you cry at my wedding.
埃迪:你看见了?
Ed: You did?
麦琪:是.
Maggie: Yep.
埃迪:那可能因为你要嫁给这么一个男人.
Ed: Well that was probably because of the guy who you were marrying.
麦琪:我不相信你.
Maggie: I don't believe you.
埃迪:好呀.
Ed: Good.
麦琪:我能为你做点什么,爸爸?
Maggie: What can I do for you dad?
埃迪:哦,我,我,我已经告诉你保险的事.那,那,那,那,安排.
Ed: Well, I, I, I told you about the insurance.The, the, the, the, arrangements.
麦琪:爸爸,请你了.
Maggie: Daddy please.
埃迪:好的,亲爱的,我恐惧.
Ed: Good honey, I'm scared.
麦琪:这真是不公平.
Maggie: It's just not fair.
埃迪:公平!公平!你是想说公平?你知道,查里 麦吉尔比我大三岁,他每天喝一四分之一瓶威士忌.还有朱尼 布格里奥斯动了那么多手术,而且从胳肢窝里排泄.他还照去高尔夫球场,很容易赚钱.过去的十年中,我一直不吃高脂肪,高胆固醇,硝酸盐,盐和不吃你妈从读者文摘上看来的那些鬼东西.胃和大肠,还有直肠.我知道的比一个肠胃专家还多.
Ed: Fair!Fair!You want to talk fair?You know that Charlie McGill who is
three years older than me?He drinks a quarter scotch a day.And that Jonnie
Buggliosi, he's had so much surgery that he eats out of his armpit.He's still
out there on the golf course making easy money out of those puts of his
For the past ten years I've avoided red meat, cholesterol, nitrate,
salt and every other
damn thing your mother could read about in the Readers Digest.
Iron Joe's stomach, Iron
Joes intestines, Iron Joes colon.I know more about Iron Joe than any stinking proctologist
麦琪:你说得对,爸爸.这不公平.
Maggie: You are right dad.It's not fair.
埃迪:而且一切消失的都那么快.哦,
Ed: And it all goes by so fast.
真抱歉从来没有去看你在大学里的圣诞节表演.
Oh I'm sorry that I never saw you in your grade school Christmas Pageant.
麦琪:哪一个?
Maggie: Which one?
埃迪:所有.因为我必须晚上干活,
Ed: All of them.
因为那是加班,我们需要钱.
Because I had to work nights because it was over time and we needed the money.
麦琪:哦,爸爸,爸爸,你不必解释了.
Maggie: Oh dad, dad, you don't have to explain.
埃迪:哦,谢谢.
Ed: Oh thanks.
麦琪:妈妈对这事真的没有意见?
Maggie: Is mum really ok with all this?
埃迪:你在开玩笑.你妈妈对此一点也不知道.
Ed: Are you kidding.Your mother doesn't know anything about this.
麦琪:爸爸,你说你告诉她了.
Maggie: Dad, you said you told her.
埃迪:不,我说她没事.她没事,是因为她什么都不知道.
Ed: No, I said she was fine.And she is fine because she doesn't know anything.
麦琪:但是,爸爸,必须得告诉她.
Maggie: But dad, she has to be told.
埃迪:我知道了.
Ed: I know.
麦琪:她有权利知道.
Maggie: She has a right to know.
埃迪:让我来给你解释一些东西.
Ed: Let me explain something to you.
真正的男人是不会让他的妻子来承受他的烦恼和忧虑.
A real man doesn't burden his wife with his worries and his doubts.
他应该做的就是如何保持婚姻美满,
His job is to keep his marriage glistening no matter how he has to suffer
无论他不得不默默承受.
in silence.
麦琪:那么妈妈不该知道你还有脆弱敏感的一面?
Maggie: So mum's not supposed to know that you have a vulnerable sensitive side.Hu
埃迪:那是我的目标.
Ed: That's been my goal.
麦琪:爸爸.
Maggie: Daddy.
埃迪:瞧,我已经照顾我的凯特四十六年了.
Ed: Look, I've taken care of my Kate for forty seven years.
她依靠我才有了力量.
She relies on me for strength.
如果她现在知道我害怕,会给她带来什么后果?
If she knows I'm afraid now, what's there left for her?
麦琪:爸爸,你不能把这一切都自己承受.
Maggie: Dad, you can't keep this all to yourself.
埃迪:我在这,不是吗?
Ed: I'm here aren't I?
麦琪:哦,是的
Maggie: Oh yeah.
埃迪:我知道另外一件怪事.
Ed: You know another strange thing.
我原来想我快死时,
I thought when my day came, I'd be able to be ready to die.
我会准备着去死.可当医生给我这个信息,
But when that doctor gave me the news,
我却感到比一生中任何时候都更加年轻和健康.
I felt younger and healthier than I've ever felt in my life.
这究竟是怎么回事?
Now what's the sense of all of that?
麦琪:我不知道,爸爸?
Maggie: I know daddy.
埃迪:当我还是年轻人的时候,
Ed: When I was a young man,
我曾经认为那些老人有所有的答案.
I used to think that old people had all the answers.
麦琪:我以为你一直有所有答案.
Maggie: I thought you had all the answers all along.
埃迪:不,我只是假装的.我们的秘密.
Ed: No, I was just faking it.Our secret.
麦琪:我们的秘密.妈妈应该被告知,爸爸.
Maggie: Our secret.Mum's got to be told dad.
埃迪:我知道,我知道.但是我首先需要和你谈谈.
Ed: I know.I know.But I needed to talk to you first.
麦琪:需要?
Maggie: Needed?
埃迪:你不小瞧我,是吗?
Ed: You don't think any less of me do you?
麦琪:哦,不,爸爸.我感到如此骄傲做你的儿子.
Maggie: Oh no daddy.I am so proud to be your son.
麦琪:哦!本,这些做的不错.
Maggie: Oh Ben, these will do just fine.
杰森:我接.
Jason: I'll get it.
本:他们是你们的.
Ben: They're yours.
麦琪:哦!我只需要他们几天.
Maggie: Oh I only need them for a couple of days.
本:我不要他们回来.我不再使用他们了,
Ben: I don't want them back.
自从他们生了虫子.
I don't use them anymore since they got bug infested.
克莉丝:我还不明白.为什么我不能和你和外公去钓鱼?
Chrissy: I still don't get it.Why can't I go fishing with you and grandpa?
麦琪:哦,亲爱的,这是个机会让外公和我谈谈.
Maggie: Oh honey, it's just a chance for grandpa and me to talk.
克莉丝:我不会说一个字.我就坐在那会乖的.
Chrissy: I won't say a word.I'll just sit there and look cute.
麦琪:哦,小甜心,
Maggie: Oh sweetheart, do you remember last month when daddy took you
你记得上个月爸爸带你去溜冰,
ice skating and you didn't want anybody else to go because you didn't
而你不让别人去,因为你不想和别人分享爸爸.
want to share him?
克莉丝:你想说什么?
Chrissy: What's your point?
麦琪:那外公是我的爸爸.
Maggie: Well grandpa is my daddy.
克莉丝:那就是为什么昨天晚上我不能和你一起送外公去飞机场.
Chrissy: And that's why last night I couldn't ride along when you dropped
gran back at the airport.
麦琪:正确.
Maggie: That's right.
克莉丝:这是种趋势?
Chrissy: Is this a trend?
麦琪:不,小甜心!嘿,我看起来怎么样?这是什么?
Maggie: No sweetheart.Hey, how do I look?What is it?
杰森:是你爸爸.他大概一个小时前去世了.
Jason: It's your dad.He died about an hour ago.
麦琪:不.不,
Maggie: No.No, I just called him this morning to see if he had a safe
早上我还打电话给他,问他旅途是否安全?
flight.
杰森:医生说他走的很快,没有痛苦.
Jason: Doctor said he went quickly and there was no pain.
麦琪:哦,不!他还邀请我去钓鱼呢.不!
Maggie: No, no!He just invited me on this fishing trip.No!
不,我们还要拣起我们所丢失的?(哭)哦,杰森.
No, we were going to pick up where we left off.(Crying) Oh Jason.
杰森:我难过.
Jason: I'm sorry.
麦琪:哦,杰森.我得打电话给妈妈.
Maggie: Oh Jason.I got to call mum.
麦琪:高点,爸爸.高点.
Maggie: Higher daddy.Higher.
埃迪:今天你打了三个好球,我的宝贝.我为你自豪.
Ed: You got three hits today my darling.I'm so proud of you.
麦琪:那么我又能涂口红了?
Maggie: So I can where lipstick again?
埃迪:是的,但不能在打球时.
Ed: Yeah, but not to practice.
麦琪:为什么不能?埃迪:因为极少涂口红的棒球手进入大联盟.
Maggie: Why not? Ed:
00:20:59,400
Well very few ballplayers who were lipstick ever make it to the big leagues.